Register of the Grigorii Nikolaevich Trubetskoi papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Obliki proshlogo, 1925 Fall; d. 104 (Reading room Workstation)
  G. N. Trubetskoi's memoir and family history, written in Fall 1925. Typescript (for the original handwritten copy, see d. 63). Includes: Sem'ia moego otsa, pages 2-18; Sem'ia moiei materi, pages 18-31; Diadia Seriozha, pages 31-51; Moi roditeli, pages 52-68; Kaluga, pages 68-79; Nashi druz'ia, pages 80-89; Gimnaziia, pages 90-91; Kaluzhskoe obshchestvo, pages 91-96; Sergievskoe, pages 97-99; Brat Serezha, pages 100-105; Moskva: Presnia, pages 106-134; Moskovskii universitet (1892-1896), pages 135-169; Staryi vostok (otryvki vospominanii), 17 pages, section on the early part of Trubetskoi's career